Finding Aid for the Paul Rotha papers LSC.2001
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Crown Film Unit cuttings, Humphrey Jennings. (Box 78, Folder 9)
- Richard Winnington book. (Box 78, Folder 10)
  Early letters, RW award, sundry: memorial service, etc.
- Manchester University. (Box 79, Folder 1)
- Winnington Book. (Box 79, Folder 2)
  Tapes, exhibition, early letters, etc.
- U.S.A. letters., 1937/1938. (Box 79, Folder 3)
- Hitler film. (Box 79, Folder 4)
  Final text and letters, etc.
- Miscellaneous items taken to U.S.A., ca. 1937. (Box 79, Folder 5)
- Cuttings., 1942/1943. (Box 79, Folder 6)
- Documents - Thompson family. (Box 80, Folder 1)
- ARFP lecture list., 1937/1938. (Box 80, Folder 2)
- U.S.A., 1937/1938. (Box 80, Folder 3)
- Hitler film. (Box 80, Folder 4)
  Research, programme.
- Real Film letters. (Box 80, Folder 5)
- Last commentary of Hitler film., July 15, 1961. (Box 80, Folder 6)
- World Union Documentary., 1947. (Box 80, Folder 7)
- Press cuttings., ca. 1976. (Box 80, Folder 8)
- Atomic energy letters. (Box 81, Folder 1)
- De Overval stills., 1962. (Box 81, Folder 2)
- No Resting Place stills (Sushitzki's rejects)., 1950. (Box 81, Folder 3)
- U.S.A. letters. (Box 81, Folder 4)
- Private correspondence. (Box 81, Folder 5)
- Mayer, Carl. (Box 82, Folder 1)
- Photographs for Biography and Documentary Diary. (Box 82, Folder 2)
- Japan. (Box 82, Folder 3)
- [Unlabeled]. (Box 82, Folder 4)
- 1983/1984. (Box 82, Folder 5)
- Income tax, National Westminister Bank Limited. (Box 82, Folder 6)
- [Magazines, newspaper cuttings]. (Box 82, Folder 7)
- [Unlabeled]. (Box 82, Folder 8)
- [Photocopy of diary notebook]. (Box 82, Folder 9)
- [Unlabeled]. (Box 82, Folder 10)
- [Address book]. (Box 83, Folder 1)
- Magazine and newspaper cuttings. (Box 83, Folder 2)
- Engravings. (Box 83, Folder 3)
- Su's photographs., 1983. (Box 83, Folder 4)
- Photographs of Eric Knight, Otto Neurath, and drawing of Paul Rotha by Bunche Lee., (ca. 1930) (Box 83, Folder 5)
- [Photographs]. (Box 83, Folder 6)
- Negatives and information for exhibiton. (Box 83, Folder 7)
- [2 Photographs]. (Box 83, Folder 8)
- Original negatives of Paul Rotha used on spine of film Till Now jacket., summer 1930. (Box 83, Folder 9)
- [Photographs folder 1 of 2]. (Box 83, Folder 10)
- [Photographs folder 2 of 2]. (Box 84, Folder 1)
- [Negatives]. (Box 84, Folder 2-4)
- Photographs of Bunche Lee, Paul Rotha's first wife., 1929. (Box 84, Folder 5)
- Last Days at College., August 1962.; Negatives and prints. (Box 84, Folder 6)
- [Unlabeled]. (Box 84, Folder 7)
- Paul Rotha Photographs., June 8, 1979. (Box 84, Folder 8)
- [World Without End parts 1-6 (2 film reels), negatives, 2 posters for the Life of Adolph Hitler]. (Box 85, Folder 1)
- Photographs of the burned out interior of the Abbey theater, undated (Box 86, Folder 1)
  2 photographs, drawings, awards, etc. Art work. See Box 23 f. 18 for partial list.
- "Paul Rotha's rendering of Greta Garbo," Ink Drawing., undated (Box 87)
  Early in Rotha's career he used his given name, Paul Thompson, before changing it, first to Paul de Rotha and then to Paul Rotha.
- Modern design, Watercolor apliqué, undated (Box 87)
- Bull, Charcoal sketch by Joan Begbie, 1924 (Box 87)
- Human bones, Illustration, undated (Box 87)
  Ink and watercolor with pencil notations
- Life drawings, undated (Box 87)
  3 charcola illustrations
- Geometrical abstract. Watercolor., undated (Box 87)
- Pastoral, ink and watercolor signed by Paul Thompson, 1928 (Box 87)
- "A Design for a Dish," watercolor, 1925 (Box 87)
- Galley, watercolor., 1924 (Box 87)
- Female nudes, charcoal sketches, 1925 (Box 87)
- Woman in chair, pencil sketch, undated (Box 87)
- Male nude, pencil sketch, 1925 (Box 87)
- "Norton 3 1/2 H P", 1920 (Box 87)
- Life drawing, 1924 (Box 87)
  October 12, 1924Pencil sketches, 2 illustrations
- Life drawing, pencil sketches, undated (Box 87)
- Male nudes, 1926 (Box 87)
  "William Drury[?] at Slade[?}, 2 pencil illustrations
- "Mary Shelly," watercolor, undated (Box 87)
  Verso: 2 chairs. 2 illustrations
- Female bust, charcoal drawing, undated (Box 87)
- Medieval castle scene, 1926 (Box 87)
  Ink and watercolor signed Paul de Rotha
- "B.L," ink illustration, undated (Box 87)
- Lady's ballgown, watercolor and ink, undated (Box 87)
- "Yvette, 1807", undated (Box 87)
  Watercolor and ink, mounted and overmatted
- An encounter in the woods, water color and ink, undated (Box 87)
- "Stage design for Richard III: London, A Street.", 1925 (Box 87)
  Ink and watercolor signed by Paul Thompson
- Hats, undated (Box 87)
  6 ink and watercolor illustrations mounted and overmatted
- "Sir Simon Addlelot", 1925 (Box 87)
  costume for Love in a Wood by Wycherley, 1671. Signed Paul Thompson, 1925. Wter color with pencil notations for costume.
- "A Wicked Rouge about 1540", 1925 (Box 87)
- "Back View of a Cavalier about 1640", 1925 (Box 87)
  Watercolor and ink illustration with pencil notations
- "Lydia" costume for Love in a Wood by Wycherley., 1925 (Box 87)
  Signed Paul Thompson. Watercolor illustration with pencil notations for costume
- "Costume for Alithea (Pinchwife's sister) in Wycherley's The Country Wife", 1926 (Box 87)
  Signed Paul Thompson. Watercolor illustration with pencil notations
- Costume design for Lydia Languish ca. 1775 for "The Rivals" by Richard Brinsley Sheridan, 1925 (Box 87)
- Costume design for "Negro Prince" costume for "A ballet Imaginaire", undated (Box 87)
  mounted watercolor
- Blonde gentleman with a yellow hose, Verso: "Barn at Stanmon", 1925 (Box 87)
  2 watercolor illustrations
- "Horseman" in orange cape and boots with spurs, 1927 (Box 87)
  repaired watercolor
- "Design for Second Cavalier" Costume for A Ballet Imaginaire, 1926 (Box 87)
- "First Cavalier" Costume for A Ballet Imaginaire, 1926 (Box 87)
  Verso: preliminary sketch for a woman's costume. 2 illustrations.
- "Third Cavalier" Costume for A Ballet Imaginaire, 1926 (Box 87)
  watercolor, partial illustration of a man
- "Messer Nello Nelli," watercolor, undated (Box 87)
- "Galeazzo Maria Sforza," watercolor, undated (Box 87)
- "Cagliostro," watercolor, undated (Box 87)
- Costume for the "Mad Marquis," watercolor, 1927 (Box 87)
- Middle-Eastern costume: genie [?], undated (Box 87)
- "Military costume of about 1830," watercolor, undated (Box 87)
  Verso: partial landscape in ink, 2 illustrations
- "Costume for Henry V Period," watercolor, undated (Box 87)
- Macheath in "The Beggar's Opera", 1926 (Box 87)
  watercolor and chalk
- "Jew Süss," watercolor, undated (Box 87)
- Scrapbook, photographs and proofs of Rotha's artwork., undated (Box 87)
  1 book, 48 illustrations.
- "Hyacinthe, Marquis de Montesquieu," ink and watercolor, undated (Box 87)
- Woman in feathered headpiece, orange robes, watercolor, 1927 (Box 87)
- Blueprints for set design, floor layout, camera set-ups for various Rotha films, undated (Box 88)
- Poster for the Academy Cinema showing of the Life of Adolf Hitler film, undated (Box 88)
- Award diplomas, undated (Box 88)
- Suzanna and the Elders, in the Watteau manner., 1926 (Box 88)
  Watercolor and ink.
- Scrapbook. Newspaper clippings by or about Rotha, about the cinema, 1944-1948 (Box 89, Folder 1)
- Art work by Rotha, undated (Box 90)
  Costume designs, set designs, graphics, pen and ink and pencil drawings, charcoal sketches.
- Set design and tempura painting, undated (Box 91)
  Tempura painting. Black and white drawing of Slum contrasted with modern housing, possibly for film "Land of Plenty."